Tony Olagbaiye

PROFILE



Born: July 1996 Nationality: Black British

Profile: A Computer Science and Maths enthusiast with experience in a variety of programming languages, platforms and development environments, and a natural penchant for developing and applying knowledge.

SKILLS

PROGRAMMING

Fluent

C • C++ • C# • Kotlin • Haskell • Rust SQL • Python2 • CSS • Shell • Go • Vala Purescript • Python3 • ŁTFX • HTML5

Competent

Java • F# • Javascript • PHP • Assembly Scheme • Typescript • OCaml • Nim

Familiar

Ruby • CLisp • Clojure Perl • Lua • Ada

LANGUAGES

Fluent

English (Native)

Competent

Japanese • Spanish

Familia

French • Italian • Mandarin • Finnish

PLATFORMS

Fluent

Linux (inc. RHEL, Debian) • FreeBSD NetBSD • POSIX • Azure • NixOS

Competent

Windows • Android • Web

Familiar

OSX • Embedded • AWS

BIOGRAPHY

I have had reasonable experience in the Tech Sector both as a student, in industry and in freelance. As a hobbyist, I am always up to date with the latest tech, conventions, and trends, and even outside quantifiable corporate experience I have years of casual experience with almost all forms of IT, from my passions in the theoretical and academic lambda calculus, to the baremetal microinstructions, which you can observe from my github.

EXPERIENCE

MAC SOLUTIONS | Senior Developer

March 2022 - December 2022 | Remote

 Functioned as the principal developer of two commercial software units in active market. Used .NET stacks, with my primary role being to modernize the code/process from .NET Framework to .NET Core, shift from loose JavaScript to a TypeScript-based system, introduce a proper testing framework and rigour, audit security practices, and shift from TFS and "nightmare collaboration" to a streamlined Azure DevOps git-based workflow.

STREELANCE | CONTRACTING

May 2021 - March 2022 | Remote

• Several unspecified independent posts developing private projects and contributing to open source software, during the commotion of pandemic lockdowns and in the interests of furthering ventures I support.

LOCATION EXTREME | LEAD DEVELOPER

March 2020 - May 2021 | Oxford / Remote

- Held my position as the lead developer on the sole project developed during
 my tenure. Worked on the cloud component of a service for managing GPS
 trackers and the .Net app services based on that service. The architecure was
 tightly built around azure, using Azure Functions for cheap execution,
 Queues and CosmosDB for light data management and pipelineing, and
 AzureSQL for the more static data (account management). App services used
 ASP.Net Core with EntityFramework and NUKE for build automation with
 Azure DevOps. The frontends were written in ReactJS. All tests were
 written in F# using FsCheck for unit testing by propositional checking and
 Xunit for functional tests.
- All tests were written in F# using FsCheck for unit testing by propositional checking and Xunit for functional tests.
- Project not completed during the global issues and an ensuing company redundancy consultation due to downsizing.

ANSWER DIGITAL | .NET DEVELOPER

July 2019 - March 2020 | Leeds

- Functioning as a mid-tier developer. First project being an NHS team integration in Manchester, colocated 3 days a week. Working on a full stack web app for client internal use with a .Net backend, Aurelia/Typescript frontend, and a combination of SQL and MongoDB for storage (depending on security requirements). Second being a pioneer greenfield project for RPMI, replacing one side of a poor quality project completed by a previous service. The client in this case decided to colocate to us, and this used a .Net backend and JQuery/vanillaJS frontend due to requirements including use of Sitefinity as a CMS. The infrastructure was entirely Microsoft technologies, primarily Azure, and the site security (which was my primary concern) was almost entirely home grown.
- Testing was executed at all levels using Jest for frontend unit acceptance, nunit for backend unit tests, and selenium/cypress for integration, with cucumber to generate expressive scenarios.
- All projects function using AGILE methodologies as a top tier requirement, with daily scrum meetings, and/or whatever form of kanban is best applicable to the task. Lastly, regularly helped with the Answer Academy to train new recruits.

MOSAIC FULFILMENT SOLUTIONS | GRADUATE DEVELOPER

Aug 2018 - Jun 2019 | Wetherby

- Took part in daily SCRUM meetings, infrastructure management and administration, full stack development and maintenance of a critical web app suite used internally and sold externally, liaising with clients and internal resources for support queries and specification, full end-to-end development of in-house data operations utilities, and most commonly SQL development and administration from the creation and maintenance of highly volatile databases containing tens of tables with millions of rows, to development of efficient and maintainable procedures and system agent jobs for data manipulation.
- Worked in Javascript/Typescript/Asp.Net-Core/Linq/SCSS, MS SQL Server 14/17, C#, using Visual Studio, VSTS/TFS, and SQL Server Management Studio.
- Developed my own C# test framework and harness to ensure robustness in a very critical and large codebase.

MUNIVERSITY OF YORK | THIRD YEAR

Sept 2017 - Jun 2018 | York

THALES UK LTD | SOFTWARE ENGINEER INTERN

June 2016 - Sept 2017 | Manchester

• Took part in day to day running of software projects and meetings, including SCRUM meetings. Worked in Javascript/AngularJS and C++/Boost, using IBM Rhapsody and Rational Clearcase.

<u>m</u> UNIVERSITY OF YORK | FIRST AND SECOND YEAR

Sept 2014 - Jun 2016 | York

☑ DULWICH COLLEGE | CHAIRMAN OF THE PROGRAMMING SOCIETY

Sept 2013 - Jun 2014 | London

 Tasked with running and maintaining DC ProgSoc, including leading weekly sessions teaching aspects of programming for new and experienced students.

EDUCATION

DULWICH COLLEGE

Graduated Aug 2014

A-Levels

A*, A in Further Maths

2 extra unaccredited maths modules

B in Physics C in Chemistry

GCSE

11 GCSEs of which 10 A*/A

(inc. Maths, English)

Chairman of the Programming

Society

Tasked with running and maintaining DC ProgSoc, including leading weekly

sessions teaching aspects of

programming for new and experienced students.

UNIVERSITY OF YORK

MMATH COMPUTER SCIENCE WITH

MATHEMATICS [GG1K]

(With a year in industry)

First Year

Theory and Practice of Programming, Computer Architecture, Mathematics of Computer Science, Core

Algebra & Calculus

Second Year

Vision and Graphics, Principles of Programming Languages, Computation and Complexity, Artificial Intelligence, Intro to Number Theory, Group Theory,

Ring Theory, Linear Algebra

Graduated Aug 2018

Third Year

Programming Correctness by Construction, Neural Computing and Applications, Information and Coding Theory, Dynamical Systems, Metric Spaces, Algebraic Number Theory, Cryptography, Topology, Galois

Theory

REFERENCES

Edward Phillips

Mosaic Manager York House Wetherby Road York, YO26 7NH 01904 202 140 edward.phillips@

Benjamin Johns

mosaic-fs.co.uk

Location Extreme Director Hampden House Monument Business Park Chalgrove Oxford, OX44 7RW 01865 528696 ben.johns@ locationextreme.co.uk

Emma Andrews

Answer People Coordinator Union Mills 9 Dewsbury Road Leeds, LS11 5DD 0113 201 0600 emma.andrews@ answerdigital.co.uk

Samir Al-Othary

MAC Solutions Manager
Tapton Park Innovation Centre
Brimington Road
Tapton, Chesterfield
Derbyshire, S41 OTZ
01246 733120
samir.a@
mac-solutions.co.uk

Typeset in LuaPTFX